<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Beans</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/beans/beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/beans/beans/</guid>
      <description>Why the Beans? People are always asking me about the Coffee beans on this site. Am I a Barista? Am I just really into coffee? What? If you look through this site for a while, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I have been involved with the Java Programming Language and Java Technology since, well, since just a little bit before Java was actually released by Sun Microsystems, Inc. back in 1995 (has it really been that long?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/introduction/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/introduction/introduction/</guid>
      <description>I said a bit about myself on my home-page, but apparently you want more information. So OK, here&amp;rsquo;s more information.
The Recent Past For about 2.5 years I was the Senior Developer Evangelist for InfluxData. It pushed me past my million miles on American Airlines (not that it gets you much, really) and has allowed me to do some really cool IoT and more specifically IoT Data stuff. See my blog for more on that!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mad Skillz</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/mad-skillz/mad-skillz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/mad-skillz/mad-skillz/</guid>
      <description>David G. Simmons davidgs@davidgs.com
   
What Do I Want? To do really cool stuff, have fun doing it, and make you the cool kids.
When Do I Want It? Now, duh.
tl;dr I can literally build it, demo it and explain it to anyone, and make them want it more than they want ice cream.
Geek Speak Java for days, C when it&amp;rsquo;s needed, Script-kiddie in Python, Bash, Javascript and a bunch more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
