<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What in the job hopping hell?</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/what-in-the-job-hopping-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/what-in-the-job-hopping-hell/</guid>
      <description>You what? I changed jobs. Again. Yes. I did. But there&amp;rsquo;s a good reason for it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that long ago that I posted about leaving InfluxData and joining QuestDB as their Head of Developer Relations. In fact, it was only 6 months ago. And yet, here I am, once again, posting about a job change. This is, you may notice, not characteristic of me. I was at Sun for 15 years, then Riverbed for 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Time Series All the Way Down</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/its-time-series-all-the-way-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/its-time-series-all-the-way-down/</guid>
      <description>As you are well aware, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing IoT for almost 20 years (yeah, not a typo!). And for the last 2.5 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been applying that IoT knowledge to Time Series Databases. Also, as you are probably aware, I am no longer at InfluxData, where I&amp;rsquo;d been doing that. Long story, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really allowed to talk about it much. One thing I have discovered over the past 2 months, since leaving InfluxData, is that it appears as though I&amp;rsquo;m the only Developer Relations Professional who actually has expertise in IoT and Time Series Databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCRIoT Meetup</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/ncriot-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/ncriot-meetup/</guid>
      <description>If you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll already know that I was at the NCRIoT IoT Meetup yesterday at the NASCAR Hall of Fame in Charlotte, NC. You may not know what NC RIoT is. Hell, until recently, I didn&amp;rsquo;t either, which is a crime really because it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing group of IoT fanatics doing some really cool stuff with IoT. I even met a guy who does as many crazy things with IoT as I do &amp;ndash; you should follow @LogicalDan on twitter, and tweet at him in case he&amp;rsquo;s wearing his shirt that lights up when you tweet at him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to Evangelism</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/return-evangelism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/return-evangelism/</guid>
      <description>Things change. What’s that saying in Computer Science? “Variables won’t. Constants aren’t.” The only thing that never changes is that everything changes. And so things are (once again) changing for me. And I do mean in a good way!
It’s been a few years, and it’s taken a fair amount of effort, but I’m moving back into the space I know the best, and where my heart lies: The Internet of Things (IoT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of the Resume</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/the-art-of-the-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/the-art-of-the-resume/</guid>
      <description>If you ask 100 people about what a resume should be, you’ll likely get close to 100 answers.
 “It should be no more than 1 page long”  “it should have a statement of objective” “never put your interested on a resume”  “only list your last 3 jobs”  And on and on. Most of it is conflicting, and pretty much none of it will work for everyone. These days, resumes are a crap-shoot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So What&#39;s With All The Jobs??</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/so-whats-with-all-the-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/so-whats-with-all-the-jobs/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been following along lately, you’ll notice that a bunch of stuff has been happening with me. First, I lost my job, Then I started a company, Dragonfly IoT, and made myself the CTO of it (because I could, you know). And yesterday I was appointed the new CTO of another startup, Chimera IoT. So that’s a lot of jobs, and a lot of CTO jobs, for just one person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulp ... I&#39;m really doing this!</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/gulp-im-really-doing-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/gulp-im-really-doing-this/</guid>
      <description>Well, as you know, I have been in the market for a new job lately. Really bad timing to be looking for a full-time gig what with the holidays, the end of many companies’ fiscal years, etc. Great timing. I decided it was time to take the bull by the horns, so to speak, and do something about it myself So I have co-founded Dragonfly IoT, a full-service IoT company. You can check out our new website (some slick HTML5 slinging involved there, if I do say so myself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shock To The System</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/a-shock-to-the-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/work/a-shock-to-the-system/</guid>
      <description>Well that was a bit of a shocker!
As you may or may not know, I’ve been working as the Chief Technology Evangelist for a startup called PsiKick for the past 7 or 8 months. They have some pretty amazing technology for potentially making the Internet of Things battery less. It’s a great company, with great, and really smart, engineers. We were doing some great things, and starting to gain some traction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
