<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All About IoT on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All About IoT on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Whole Thing Stinks!</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/this-whole-thing-stinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/this-whole-thing-stinks/</guid>
      <description>First of all, don&amp;rsquo;t ask I have no idea where this idea came from, it just happened. I keep saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not especially proud of this&amp;rdquo; but in reality? I sort of am because it&amp;rsquo;s funny as shit (pun intended). Some projects came across my twitter feed that included (I shit you not) a 3-D printable model of the 💩 emoji. I remember nothing else about that project, but you&amp;rsquo;d better believe that I went straight for that STL file!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensing with The Things Network</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/sensing-with-the-things-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/sensing-with-the-things-network/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to connect your sensors to the network in the IoT. For short-range connections, there is Bluetooth LE, or Zigbee, or 802.15.4, or ZWave. For longer distances (though still fairly short) there’s always WiFi. But when you need longer distances, sometimes very long distances, there’s LoRaWAN. It’s a sub-gigahertz set of frequencies that are available for small bits of data. These are typically only a few bytes of data but can be sent over much longer distances — up to 2 km or more in some instances!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Haven&#39;t Seen Big Data Yet</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/you-havent-seen-big-data-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/you-havent-seen-big-data-yet/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I know, &amp;ldquo;Big Data&amp;rdquo; as a buzz-word is so 5 minutes ago. The tech world is chronically ADD and prone to being distracted by the next shiny object (OOh! Look, IoT!, Wait, AI! SQUIRREL!!) But stay with me on this. It&amp;rsquo;s all connected. I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying since at least 2005 (back when Big Data was all the rage) that you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen truly big data until the IoT truly gets going in full force.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Distance</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/playing-with-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/playing-with-distance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with a bunch of different sensors lately (see here) so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do another little write-up of it. I dug my Particle Photon out to play with after being inspired at an NC RIoT event a few weeks ago and it had been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;d had it out. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to share the exact problem I was trying to solve with this little application, as it&amp;rsquo;s still a work in progress and may very well end up being a product soon, but I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how I&amp;rsquo;m doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The (Updated) Big Board of IoT</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-updated-big-board-of-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-updated-big-board-of-iot/</guid>
      <description>You may recall that at one point a year ago I posted a picture of my &amp;ldquo;Big Board of IoT Development&amp;rdquo;. I had a half dozen or so IoT development nodes and some sensors on it that I was working on. Since then, things have gotten significantly worse &amp;ndash; or better, depending on your point of view. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d drop another picture on you. {width=&amp;ldquo;600&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;450&amp;rdquo;}
So obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t use all those boards on the giant breadboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your ARTIK-520 Scream</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/make-your-artik-520-scream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/make-your-artik-520-scream/</guid>
      <description>If you read last week&amp;rsquo;s post about making an ARTIK-520 an IoT gateway device using the Eclipse Kura project, then this will be a noticeable improvement for you if you&amp;rsquo;re going to try it yourself (and why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you? It was an excellent little How To on getting started with ARTIK-520 and IoT!)
It was suggested to me (these little birdies keep feeding me interesting nuggets to try) that I try the Azul Zulu Embedded JVM as an alternative to the OpenJDK JVM that is installed by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Winter Vacation (what I did with IoT and ARTIK-5)</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/winter-vacation-iot-artik-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/winter-vacation-iot-artik-5/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, or what you did with your winter vacation (or if you even got one, and if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry) but one of the fun things I did with mine was to spend a little time with my Samsung ARTIK Dev Kit. If you read the Hardware Extravaganza Post, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I got an ARTIK-0 and an ARTIK-5 developer kit not long ago. I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to my ears in MyNewt though and haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to do much with them, sadly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Big Board of IoT Devices</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-big-board-of-iot-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-big-board-of-iot-devices/</guid>
      <description>Just for future reference, here’s the development board that sits on my desk:
What’s on it? Well, here’s the list:
 Intel Edison: One on the (mostly useless) Intel Mini Breakout board and one on a Sparkfun Block (more on this one in a later post) Electric Imp A couple of Arduinos — they’re actually RFDuinos, which I backed on Kickstarter. A Particle Photon A NodeMCU Some random sensors I’m working with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Switching from Tile to Trakr</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/why-im-switching-from-tile-to-trakr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/why-im-switching-from-tile-to-trakr/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a loyal Tile user since I first baked their Kickstarter project. I love the idea of being able to locate things I lose all the time, like my keys, and to keep track of stuff I might lose, like my DSLR, my GoPro, etc. I even used them to keep track of my cats when they wee indoor-outdoor cats. I at least knew when they were around even if I couldn’t find them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Minor IoT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/minor-iot-calculations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/minor-iot-calculations/</guid>
      <description>Batteries will be a limiting factor in IoT deployments There’s a lot of hype about the Internet of Things (IoT) as I’ve said repeatedly — and as anyone who’s reading anything about technology these days already knows. There’s wearable tech, there’s healthcare IoT, there’s M2M IoT and a host of other areas of the IoT that are all projected to explode over the next 10 years. Billions and billions of devices are forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is IoT Happening or Not in 2015?</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/is-iot-happening-or-not-in-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/is-iot-happening-or-not-in-2015/</guid>
      <description>It’s clear that IoT is the buzzword of the minute. Maybe the buzzword of the year. Everyone’s talking about it, mentioning it, making predictions about it and claiming to be a player in it. I am among those, but I have the background and the history to back it up. But after reading this article from Electronics Weekly.com, I’m just aggravated. It is annoyingly titled “The Internet of Things is Not Happening” which is just plain wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IoT Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-iot-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/the-iot-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>What is the Internet of Things (IoT) anyway? And what makes up the IoT ecosystem? Yes, IoT is the buzzword of the year. Yes, everyone thinks everything is IoT these days. But just because a thing connects to the internet doesn’t mean it’s IoT.
In thinking about this idea, I put together the following presentation, of sorts. It’s HTLM5, and can take a while to load, but check it out and let me know what you think in the comments section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is, and isn&#39;t, IoT</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/what-is-and-isnt-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/what-is-and-isnt-iot/</guid>
      <description>So what, exactly, is the Internet of Things (IoT)? And what isn’t it? That depends on whom you ask, and what you mean. There are tons and tons of ‘connected’ gadgets that people call IoT devices.But are they really IoT devices? The Internet of Things is, loosely, the world of connected, internet-enabled devices. But let’s turn to Wikipedia, just for fun:
 The Internet of Things (IoT) is the interconnection of uniquely identifiable embedded computing devices Internet infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s Going to Drive IoT Innovation</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/whos-going-to-drive-iot-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/whos-going-to-drive-iot-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Let’s face it, the Internet of Things (IoT) is hot right now. And it’s only going to get hotter. Everyone wants in on the perceived coming gold rush that will be the Internet of Things. And a gold rush is most definitely predicted! Gartner has said so here, and here. IDCsays so, too. I could go on and list how many analysts and media pundits, etc. agree, but that would just be redundant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
