<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming the ARTIK-0 IoT Devices</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/programming-the-artik-0-iot-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/programming-the-artik-0-iot-devices/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve read this blog much at all you’ll have noticed that I’ve been a fairly big fan of the ARTIK line of IoT boards (see here, here, here, here, here, here , here and here) but I really need to clarify that a bit now. I love my ARTIK-520 board. It runs the entire InfluxData stack nicely and is a solid, reliable place to deploy IoT-Edge software. I really like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here&#39;s Why I&#39;m giving up on MyNewt (for now)</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/heres-why-im-giving-up-on-mynewt-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/heres-why-im-giving-up-on-mynewt-for-now/</guid>
      <description>With all these sensors and platforms lying around, I wanted to just pick one and build a quick sensor demo. It should be easy, right?
The basic idea As you may (or may not) know, I spent a lot of time with the Apache MyNewt project a year or so ago. It has enormous potential. It’s small, fast, and very lightweight. I even wrote a tutorial on developing an app with MyNewt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARTIK-520 as a Droplit.io Edge Device</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/artik-520-droplit-io-edge-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/artik-520-droplit-io-edge-device/</guid>
      <description>Doing some further work with my trusty ARTIK-520 (hey, when you have a hammer, everything looks like a nail! Back up off me! ) I decided to try installing another IoT Gateway framework on it. (I&amp;rsquo;ve done that before.) Equal opportunity and all that. And I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing more of them as soon as I get more mini-SD Cards in-house. But I digress.
I originally just followed the basic install instructions for deploying a Droplit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an App with Apache MyNewt</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/building-an-app-with-apache-mynewt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/building-an-app-with-apache-mynewt/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time over the last few months working on the Apache MyNewt IoT OS. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what that is, then you really should! It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly new Apache Project, still in the &amp;lsquo;incubating&amp;rsquo; phase, but they&amp;rsquo;re about to release their second beta of the 1.0 release (I think all the votes are in to approve it). Yes, there are some things still missing, and some rough edges, but it&amp;rsquo;s coming together nicely and if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an Open Source IoT OS for your device, MyNewt may just what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mynewt iOS And Mac Apps</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/mynewt-ios-mac-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-software/mynewt-ios-mac-apps/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of work on the Mynewt OS Project over at the Apache Software Foundation. It&amp;rsquo;s still &amp;lsquo;incubating&amp;rsquo; so it&amp;rsquo;s not a full-fledged Apache project yet, but we&amp;rsquo;re making huge progress and it&amp;rsquo;s coming along nicely. In fact, we&amp;rsquo;re just releasing our first beta versions of the 1.0 release! If you&amp;rsquo;re an IoT hacker, and are looking for a small, fast, highly configurable (and open source!) RTOS, MyNewt it the ticket!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
