<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programmming on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programmming on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiding Complexity with Custom Functions Calculating Heat Index</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/hiding-complexity-with-custom-functions-calculating-heat-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/hiding-complexity-with-custom-functions-calculating-heat-index/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever watched the local weather — or The Weather Channel — and heard them announce the temperature, and then the &amp;ldquo;Heat Index&amp;rdquo;? Or how hot it feels outside? At least here in the United States, and especially in the South, it&amp;rsquo;s part of every weather broadcast in the summer. But have you ever wondered how they actually calculate the Heat Index? Since I collect temperature and humidity data, I decided one day I&amp;rsquo;d go and figure it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Golang</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/adventures-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/adventures-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>I’m not a Golang developer. Let’s just get that out of the way up front. I’ve developed a few things in Go, but a Go developer I’m not. I sort of need to be, but it hasn’t been essential. I decided that it was really time to take the plunge and get serious about Go. Seriously, there’s only so much you can learn by reading the internet.
To that end, I have taken 2 actions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving a Traveling Salesman Problem</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/solving-a-traveling-salesman-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/programming/solving-a-traveling-salesman-problem/</guid>
      <description>It’s not IoT, but still … Here’s the background on this project, and why I undertook it.
For the past 3 years or so my wife and I have been volunteering with the blind in our community. Every month our church organizes a dinner for the blind in the area and we drive around and pick up participants, take them to the church where we serve everyone dinner, and the drive them all home.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
