<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on David G. Simmons</title>
    <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on David G. Simmons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quickly Connect an Argon IoT Device to QuestDB</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/quickly-connect-an-argon-iot-device-to-questdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/quickly-connect-an-argon-iot-device-to-questdb/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back to Particle.io again. I saw that they were having a 30% off sale on the new Argon and some developer kits, so I had to jump on it, since I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten any new Particle hardware in years. So, what follows is a complete guide to connecting one of these kits to QuestDB in order to store the data, and then building a dashboard on top of it with Grafana .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rev&#39;ing the Demo Hardware</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/reving-the-demo-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/reving-the-demo-hardware/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been reading me for any length of time at all, you’ll know that I build lots of little hardware projects. What better way to highlight the IoT capabilities of InfluxDB than to build hardware that writes data to it constantly! But some of my hardware demos have been getting old, and some of them have been getting abused, so I decided it was time to revamp them with some new hardware, I’m even going to make them fully wireless by adding LiPo batteries so they can go mobile during presentations and demos!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an InfluxDB IoT Edge Data Collection Device</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/building-an-influxdb-iot-edge-data-collection-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/building-an-influxdb-iot-edge-data-collection-device/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been saying I was going to write this whole project up for some time now but it has been such a daunting task that I’ve been putting it off, starting and stopping, and generally not getting it done for a few months. Finally, I have it! This is both a hardware build and a software build, and there are a lot of moving parts, so be prepared!
Overview I wanted to build a demonstration system that would show off the capabilities of using InfluxData — the entire TICK Stack — on the extreme edge of an IoT Architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building An IoT Gateway Device for local Alerting and Data Downsampling</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/building-an-iot-gateway-device-for-local-alerting-and-data-downsampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/building-an-iot-gateway-device-for-local-alerting-and-data-downsampling/</guid>
      <description>There are all sorts of ways to architect your IoT Deployment, and what’s right for one enterprise will not necessarily be right for another. Depending on the size and complexity of your IoT project , there can be, of course, a lot of components. One of the more universal architectures is to deploy sensor hubs or gateway devices to collect data from a number of sensor nodes and then forward that data on to an upstream data collection system for the enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Renesas IoT Fast Prototyping Kit</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/getting-started-with-the-renesas-iot-fast-prototyping-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/getting-started-with-the-renesas-iot-fast-prototyping-kit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to get to this for a couple of weeks, and have been waylaid by a bunch of other things that kept popping up, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been working away with these, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d post at least an initial post about these kits. Renesas was kind enough to give me both theS3 IoT Fast Prototyping Kit and the S7 Starter Kit, both of which are really really nice boards for doing IoT prototyping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfluxDB on ARTIK-520 Redux</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/influxdb-on-artik-520-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/influxdb-on-artik-520-redux/</guid>
      <description>Last week I wrote a piece on installing and running the InfluxDB time series database, ingestion, dashboard and action packages on your ARTIK-520, but I need to update that post, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more than just a few edits. Influx Data supplies the Linux binaries as packages for most of the major distributions, but the ARM distribution is just as a binary, with no package installation scripts, etc. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d show you how (and why) I fixed that for my ARTIK-520.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running InfluxDB on an ARTIK-520</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/running-influxdb-on-an-artik-520/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/running-influxdb-on-an-artik-520/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, the IoT is about data. I said it just a few weeks ago. It&amp;rsquo;s about collecting data. Lots of data. But it&amp;rsquo;s actually about a lot more than just collecting data. Simply collecting data doesn&amp;rsquo;t really get you anywhere if all you do is collect it. To be useful, IoT data has to be relevant, accurate, and actionable. That last part is the key, really. Actionable data. In order to make your data actionable, you have to be able to analyze it, in real time preferably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing your Raspberry Pi Zero W</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/accessing-your-raspberry-pi-zero-w/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/accessing-your-raspberry-pi-zero-w/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky enough to get your hands on a Raspberry Pi Zero W, then you might enjoy this. If you&amp;rsquo;re still waiting for one, bookmark this. Unless you happen to have extra HDMI monitors, keyboards and mice lying around. I don&amp;rsquo;t, so configuring mine was a pain in the ass. I&amp;rsquo;ve solved that pain for you, so read on.
First, of course, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to download and install the latest Raspian-OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenHAB Server on ARTIK-520</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/openhab-server-artik-520/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/openhab-server-artik-520/</guid>
      <description>As I said earlier, when you have a hammer &amp;hellip; So I decided to set up Yet Another IoT Gateway. This time I took a look at OpenHAB the &amp;ldquo;vendor and technology agnostic open source automation software for your home.&amp;rdquo; Why not, right? I&amp;rsquo;ve already set up a Droplit.io edge server, and an Eclipse Kura server, so why not give one more a try right? Right. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Edison Update</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-update/</guid>
      <description>I need to amend my previous post about the Intel Edison. It turns out it may not be the Edison module itself but rather the Intel Mini-Breakout Board that is at fault when t comes to at least the I2C failure. I still have to see about the SPI failures. Here’s why I have reached that conclusion:
I ordered some of the Sparkfun Blocks for Intel Edison© and went back to fooling with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Edison Big Hat, No Cattle</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-big-hat-no-cattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-big-hat-no-cattle/</guid>
      <description>It was almost exactly a year ago that I bought my first Intel Edison development kit. I was all excited about the prospects of it, as you can see here. It’s a nice, small, powerful (if power-hungry) IoT board that held a lot of promise for development and prototyping.
I wish I were still as excited about it. I’ve tried, a couple of times, to use it for some development project or another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Hardware</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/new-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/new-hardware/</guid>
      <description>I should have posted this back in October, but a few things happened. So I’m posting it now. I saw a few articles on the Spark.io board a while back, and had been anxiously awaiting its release. Then I got really really busy, and forgot all about it. Then I got unbusy again, and lo and behold, it was now called particle.io, and they had a few different boards. The Photon and the Electron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disney And #IoT</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/disney-and-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/disney-and-iot/</guid>
      <description>Over the holidays a friend of mine took her family to Disney World for a few days. They stayed at a resort in the park, paid extra for shorter lines at the rides, and were there in a group of 12. That’s a epic trip probably worthy of it’s own blog post — somewhere else. I couldn’t imagine the logistics of such a visit, but then again, it’s been 10 years since I’ve been to Disney World, and apparently a lot has changed in that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intel Edison IoT Board</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-iot-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/intel-edison-iot-board/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading about the Intel Edison development board for a while. I’m doing more IoT stuff again — purely for fun, since no one’s paying me to do it — and I’ve recently acquired the electric imp development kit and this Intel Edison kit, as well as an Arduino kit. The Intel Edison board is by far the most powerful of the bunch. It is an IoT SoC device that appeared to be extremely capable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m an IoT Imp!</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/im-an-iot-imp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/im-an-iot-imp/</guid>
      <description>I got my electric imp and imp breakout board from SparkFun last week, and I decided to check it out today and see what I could do with it in an hour. I&amp;rsquo;m re-stocking my Internet of Things (IoT) bag of tricks, and this is the first device I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten in a while, so here&amp;rsquo;s how that went.
Of course I have the requisite unpacking porn.
It’s actually a pretty nice bit of kit, with a Cortex M3 stuffed into a SSD Memory Card form factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop a Brick On It</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/drop-a-brick-on-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/drop-a-brick-on-it/</guid>
      <description>I’m all about connectivity. Yes, there are times to disconnect from the world, but that’s a personal disconnect. Applications and devices should, for the most part, be connected all the time. But connectivity is expensive and hard to maintain in remote places. If you’re connecting a server, or your house, there are many options available — let’s just go with that for now, shall we? The whole ISP monopoly issue will just get me wound up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Button</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/making-a-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/making-a-button/</guid>
      <description>I can’t resist. I mean really. Who doesn’t need a big red button that you can program to … act like a big red button? But it’s so much more than just a button! I mean, a button is just something you push, right? This? This is so much more!
 The bttn communicates with the powerful bt.tn servers in the cloud. They dispatch messages and actions to almost any internet services so that what you want gets done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gadget Freak</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/gadget-freak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 19:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/gadget-freak/</guid>
      <description>I freely admit that I am a gadget freak. I’ll also (sometimes) admit that it’s a problem. I bought a Cookoo Watch as a Kickstarter Backer of the project. I own a FitBit — I’m on my third one, don’t ask. I’ll probably buy an Apple Watch. But one of the problems I have with most ‘wearable tech’ is that, well, it looks too much like tech. The Cookoo Watch was a great start, but the first version was really buggy and unstable — except as a watch — and I’ve come to find out that it’s un-upgradeable and is basically a paperweight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Junkie</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/hardware-junkie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 19:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/hardware-junkie/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so in addition to being a gadget freak, I’m a hardware junkie. It’s been a while since I’ve actually done much hardware hackery, but that’s not because of a lack of desire. I bought an RFDuino dev kit last year as a Kickstarter backer that I just opened last weekend, and I haven’t done much with it so far. Turns out having nothing but BTLE is a lot less useful than I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Extravaganza</title>
      <link>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/hardware-extravaganza/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidgs.com/posts/category/iot/iot-hardware/hardware-extravaganza/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a minute since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted anything new, and I apologize to anyone that follows along here and has missed my posting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit busy lately with the MyNewt Operating System for IoT. It&amp;rsquo;s new, it&amp;rsquo;s cool, and it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work right now. That being said, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a minute to show off some of the new hardware I have to add to the Big Board of IoT on my desk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
